♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next sunday, a.d. ♪
♪ There was a guy
named joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn’t like him ♪
♪ so they shot him
into space ♪
♪ we’ll send him
cheesy movies ♪
- ♪ the worst we can find ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ he’ll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
- ♪ and we’ll monitor his mind ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ now keep in mind
joel can’t control ♪
- ♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
Let’s go.
- Cambot.
- Pan left.
Hi, girl.
What a cool guy.
A wisecracker.
♪ If you’re wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
- ♪ and other science facts ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself
"it’s just a show ♪
♪ "I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for... ♪
Oh! Come on, gypsy.
I can’t hold
this position forever.
I’m cramping!
Hurry up.
All right, next time gypsy
does the special effects
and i’ll direct.
Quiet on the set!
In this scene, crow,
you’re a little girl,
and you climbed up
on a stack of boxes
containing highly
flammable pajamas.
Yeah.
Okay. Action.
Make ’em hot.
Fire it up.
Hi, everybody. Welcome
to the satellite of love.
I’ve allowed the bots
to tape a spontaneous,
funny home video
for america’s
goofiest home videos.
So here’s to risking your life
in the interest of some
national tv exposure.
Let’s go.
Hey, where’s magic voice?
Ah,
she walked off the set.
She’s sulking
in her trailer.
Quiet!
Stay in character, crow.
Okay.
You’re a three-year-old girl
on a box
of flammable pajamas.
Start acting like it!
Hit ’em with the fire, tom!
Fire in the hole!
I--i changed my mind!
[Screaming]
I’m on fire! Oh,
what a world, what a world.
What a wor--aah!
Nope, it’s you,
all right, crow.
Oh, okay. Let’s watch the tape.
See how it turned out, okay?
Go ahead.
[Laughter]
Ah, you’re right.
That’s pretty funny.
That’s great.
Now, uh, how you feeling
about your arm?
It’s all gnarled.
I can make you a new one
if you like.
No, I like it
all gnarled like that.
It looks real tough.
Oh, okay.
Well, the mads are calling.
Ah, it does my heart good
to see crow burned
beyond all recognition.
Oh, frank, uh, it’s time
to reveal this week’s
invention exchange.
[Crying]
Oh, accept the pain, frank.
I know.
You’ve heard the expression
"that’s a hard pill
to swallow."
Well, our invention exchange
this week is just that.
Some hard pills to swallow.
You see this pill
right here?
That should be easy to swallow,
shouldn’t it, frank?
Yes. It should be easy,
except for the three-prong
fish-hook attached to it.
Uh, this pill,
i’m not gonna kid you,
this is very difficult
to swallow.
It’s a not-so-tiny
time pill
complete with a living gerbil.
Terry, no!
[Crying continues]
Oh, terry, yes.
If you can keep it down,
you have a pet that knows you
inside and out.
Turn, frank.
And cough.
If you have trouble
keeping one pill down,
try our pill necklace
of picric acid.
105 capsules on a string.
Keep your gag reflex active
till the cows come home.
The longer
it takes to swallow,
the harder it gets.
Yes. And the children.
- The children love...
- Ah, the children!
Vitamin shapes
shaped like cartoons.
Whimsical shapes.
And wouldn’t it be hard
on all those flintstone kids
if their favorite
cartoon vitamin came...
Turn, frank.
Life-size. Hmm? Hmm?
Ball’s in your court,
joel.
Well, that is dark, sirs.
Well, anyway,
we’ve gotten together
and come up with this celebrity
home appliances,
like this,
the emilio este-pez.
Just lift his head
and out comes real pez.
Hey,
tastes like real chalk.
Like I said, real pez.
Hey, check it out.
Here’s tom servo modeling
the jimmy j.J. Walker.
Keeps me walking,
standing upright.
Turns an ordinary stroll
dyn-o-mite!
Hey, go on the sullivan show
and get canned with this.
Your own jackie mason jar.
Who’s lifting my top?
A gentile would
do it differently?
His lifting my top
would be the thrill of his life.
A jewish man could lift
the top and say, "oy vey,
"i’m jewish.
I’m canning tomatoes.
I don’t understand it.
I got a mason jar."
And, finally,
massage a friend with this,
the charlie callas
massager.
Higher, higher.
What do you think, sirs?
I think you die, joe.
Well, your experiment
this week
is going to be hard
to keep down.
It’s called the unearthly,
and it stars john carradine
and tor johnson.
Plus two stinky shorts.
Frank, shut up!
[Frank crying loudly]
Enjoy.
[Alarm buzzing, screaming]
Avis films.
We try harder.
I think he’s still
smoldering over there.
Huh.
Hey, it’s whistler’s mother.
[Laughter]
I am whistler’s mother.
The story
you are about to see is true.
No names were changed,
because no one was innocent.
[Chuckles, imitates music]
My name’s sally.
I’m a snack-aholic.
Hi, sally.
...third grade class
at valley school
is taking a posture test.
Each girl...
- And boy...
- Oh.
- Stands behind the screen--
- it’s pudd’nhead.
To make a sharp, clear shadow
for everyone to see.
You can see that this boy
needs help.
He’s a loser, and the kids
let him know it.
Thank you. Next.
Oh.
The teacher, ms. Martin,
draws a picture
of each girl and boy.
She’s weird,
which results in creativity.
Then she shows what is wrong
when a child does not
stand straight and tall.
- It’s imogene coca!
- Yeah.
Ick.
Ms. Martin asks the class
to remember four important
things about posture.
And these four children
are especially interested
in the four important things.
- ’cause they’re on the payroll.
- Ah.
First, good health
helps you have good posture.
Tommy understands this,
because he wants
to be an athlete.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
He knows
that good health habits
are very important
to an athlete.
Amazing physique
for an eight-year-old.
Mm-hmm.
Second, good posture
keeps you from being tired.
When you stand off-balance
like this house,
your muscles must work hard
to keep you
from falling over.
I like her.
[Laughs]
Jimmy likes to build things,
so he understands
that standing straight
is standing strong,
like a tall, strong building.
- Like a spartan god.
- Wow.
Third, it is important
to have the habit
of good posture.
Your body
is like a growing tree.
With dutch elm disease.
Jane loves trees.
She knows that a young tree
must be kept straight,
so it will grow tall
and beautiful.
Don’t you, jane?
Jane!
[Whispers]
Jane.
The...larch.
Fourth, the way you look
can depend upon
your posture.
When you slump, you look
tired and unhappy.
But when you stand tall,
you look cheerful and bright.
Like a man.
Mary understands this.
Mary wants to be an actress.
She knows that an actress
must stand straight and tall
to look beautiful and happy.
Fingers on the...
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I’m wearing
a lovely pantsuit.
Ms. Martin tells the class
- that someday soon...
- She’ll be married.
After the next posture test,
they will choose
a king, a queen,
a prince,
and a princess of posture.
The two boys and the two girls
with the best postures
will wear
these posture crowns.
Yeah,
they’ll go to burger king
and get crappy hats.
Tommy, jimmy, jane, and mary
are very interested
in this announcement.
Hey, who wouldn’t be?
So when class is over,
they decide
to take a close look
at their posture drawings.
That’s when the kids
came up with a plan
to blackmail mrs. Reedy.
But they’re not happy
with what they see.
They’re disgusted
and filled with self loathing.
For tommy is indeed surprised,
and he’s not pleased
by what he found.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
No. Uh-uh.
He didn’t know his chest
looked flat
because his tummy
looked so round.
He’s got v.P.L.
Hey, let me tell you.
Joel!
Now jimmy is disturbed
to see...
Uh-uh. No. Nothin’ doing.
That ain’t gonna work.
It’s not flying with me, pops.
Out of balance, just like
a house about to fall.
Just like his dad
on friday night.
Ouch.
And what gives jane
her worried frown?
Valium?
Look at the board.
It’s plain to see
that jane
must practice
standing straight
to grow up
like a lovely tree.
All of a sudden
it’s iambic pentameter here.
Our mary is a happy girl,
so she is shocked to see instead
a droopy girl drawn on the board
with hallow chest
and tired head.
She should just
go home to bed.
- D’oh.
- Green eggs and ham.
You sam I am?
Ms. Martin sees
that the children
are especially interested,
so she offers to help them
improve their positions.
Uh-huh.
First, she shows them
the importance
of good foot position.
Uh, ms. Martin has a little
too much free time
on her hands.
- Toes point straight forward...
- There’s no place like home.
- Weight of the body...
- Hooves. Oh.
On the heel and ball
of both feet.
First down...Down...
Goal to go...Go...
Eyes are straight.
The abdomen is in.
The back is straight.
Arms swing
easily at the sides.
[Whistles]
Here she reenacts
her first d.U.I.
Get up.
Come up here.
In a good standing position--
hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey.
Back is straight,
you stretch tall.
Arms are easy at the sides.
Eyes straight ahead,
shoulders relaxed.
And you truck
like the doodah man.
Ooh.
Got your chips cashed in.
In good sitting position,
both feet
are flat on the floor.
Assuming
they reach the floor.
Hoo-hoo.
Hips are well back
against the chair.
Mm-hmm.
Crow.
Forearms and hands
are relaxed on the desk.
Pelvis.
What about the pelvis?
Elvis.
Ms. Martin suggests
that tommy and jimmy
and jane and mary
be posture pals
to help one another.
And she reminds them
of the posture contest.
[Imitating slurping]
The children
do help one another.
Jimmy helps tommy
to keep his tummy in.
You have got
to be kidding me, pyle.
Look at that gut.
Tommy reminds jimmy.
That’s you.
When jimmy stands off-balance.
Tears of shame
pour down tommy’s face.
Ms. Martin,
tommy drew a bong.
Huh?
Mary always reminds jane
when jane forgets to stand
straight and tall.
Wait a minute.
Spot for me, honey. Will you?
There.
A playground where apes
evolve from men?!
[Imitates ape]
And jane reminds mary
when mary
slumps at her desk.
Oh, they’re gonna take this
for about a half hour
before they end up
killing each other.
Yeah, I think so.
The children have other
posture pals at home.
Hey, mom’s dress
matches the wallpaper.
Night, hef.
Tommy’s mother helps him
to get plenty of sleep.
Sleep!
And plenty of good,
healthful food
so he’ll stay
healthy and strong.
Four food groups.
Hmm.
Jimmy’s father reminds jimmy
when he stands off-balance.
An airplane
shouldn’t stand crooked.
Like daddy on friday night.
Ah.
So jimmy remembers
a boy shouldn’t either.
Nor should he wear
tacky hawaiian shirts.
Jane’s father has a way
of reminding jane
when she forgets.
All right, honey,
i’m gonna kill this tree
if you don’t stand straight.
A young plant
shouldn’t be bent like that.
Then stop doing it.
Then jane remembers.
- A girl shouldn’t either.
- Oh, yeah.
- A girl?
- What?
Mary has two posture pals
at her home.
Mary’s mother reminds her
not to slump
when she’s sitting down.
It’s ernest borgnine.
Ugh.
Uh, sorry, mom, dad.
Painting her teeth.
And bombo reminds her...
Bombo?
...you look tired and unhappy.
Bombo.
Doesn’t bombo look tired?
Yes, very much so.
But now you see it was
just because...
No, no, my spine! Aah!
[Imitating bones cracking]
At last
the big day has come.
The class is taking
their second posture test.
[Imitating funeral march
of a marionette]
- It’s hitchcock.
- Yeah. After slim-fast.
Ms. Martin
is counting votes
to see who will be
the king, queen,
prince,
and princess of posture.
And who will have
a sealy posturepedic childhood.
Who did this? Did you do this?
Who did this? Who did this?
It shouldn’t be hard
for you to guess
who wins the votes.
That’s right.
Mary is elected queen.
Fix! It’s a rig! Fix!
Then mary’s head
is lit on fire.
And the other three children
win the other
posture crowns.
Definitely a fix.
Don’t you agree that these
four children deserve to win
after trying so hard
to improve their postures?
[All]
No.
Yes, tommy is our posture king.
While jimmy is the prince,
you see.
Jane is now the princess fair,
and mary
is our happy queen.
They’re the posture posse.
These boys and girls
won posture crowns
by helping one another learn.
They hope that you
will learn from them
and be a posture pal in turn.
Their chances of being cool
are ruined for life.
Bye, kids.
[Laughs]
Next week,
posture poke--in color.
[Mutters]
Hey, reuben hill.
You still walk
the fertile fields of my mind.
Oh, professor
in family life.
That’s an easy major.
This is the story
of a boy named tommy
and how he learned all--
mother do for him.
- Huh?
- This is tommy’s room.
Can you guess
what he’s thinking?
What a dump!
Look how neat and straight
his whole room is.
Hmm.
Tommy’s thinking hard,
because he hasn’t done
a thing to his room
since he left
for school this morning,
and when he left, the room
didn’t look like this at all.
He’s in the wrong house.
Toys on the shelves,
bed neatly made.
Clothes put away.
No, this morning
it looked like this.
Had more of
a queen anne theme to it.
Yeah.
Clothes scattered about.
Toys on the floor.
Beer cans everywhere.
Yes, when tommy went
to school this morning,
he left his room a mess.
- But now...
- Hey.
Everything
is neat and straight.
Except for his mind.
Now how do you suppose
that happens?
What is this crap?
And that’s not all.
Yesterday, tommy tore the sleeve
of his favorite cowboy shirt...
In a prison break.
And now it’s mended
as good as new.
Tommy’s the lathe of heaven.
And his jacket
had a button off.
Now there’s a new button.
Hmm.
And, you know,
things of that sort
don’t happen
just in tommy’s room.
They happen
all over the house.
It’s called guilt,
and boy does it work.
After breakfast this morning,
the kitchen looked like this.
Then do you know what happened
while tommy was in school?
Someone stole everything.
Yes, the table was cleared,
the dishes
were washed and put away,
and the whole kitchen
was cleaned up.
By a woman with no career
outside the house.
The same thing happened
with the dirty clothes.
They get washed and ironed
and put away just like magic.
Magic’s easy
once you know mom.
And the groceries
that come from the stores.
Well, see that chicken?
Where? Where? Oh.
Here’s the way it looks
when tommy sits down to supper.
- Ugh.
- Trumpy, no!
That reminds me.
I gotta go freshen up.
Things certainly do happen
while tommy’s in school.
Mm-hmm.
Now what does tommy see?
It’s tommy’s connection
coming up the walk.
Where’s he going?
Oh, here’s tommy’s father,
home from work.
But tommy
calls many men "dad."
- Hey, you look good.
- Oh, look really good, crow.
Hello, master.
Tommy likes
to be with his parents.
And this evening
is a little special,
for it’s the day for tommy
to receive his allowance.
Here’s a penny.
Happy birthday.
...father comes home with money
for tommy and for mother.
Eh, I suppose you want some.
...money father earns
by going out...
Here’s a dollar. Go buy
yourself something pretty.
After supper,
the kitchen looks very much
as it did after breakfast.
Ugh.
Do you know who’ll clean it up?
The maid?
Tommy knows that when
he gets up tomorrow morning,
everything’ll be done.
So goodnight, father.
Goodnight, mother.
Goodnight, oedipus.
Goodnight.
[Kisses]
Sleep.
No, help! There’s an announcer
under my bed!
Now the faces
of those he’s wronged
flash before his eyes.
Whoops. Almost forgot
something very important.
To pay homage to gorto.
He’d better put
the allowance money
in his bank
before he forgets.
Yeah, you wouldn’t want
that penny just sitting out.
But, say,
that’s not very much money.
Uh-uh.
And there are shows
to go to.
Mm-hmm.
And that super atomic
airplane to send for.
Mm-hmm.
Well, there are so many things
a boy likes
to have money for.
Like play the numbers.
Tommy’s going downstairs.
He’s going to ask father
if he can’t have a little
more money every week.
But first he straps gophers
to his feet.
Bye.
And tommy will get to see
what mother and father
do after supper.
And what all
the yelling’s about.
Yeah.
Mom? Dad?
[Gasps] Oh, my god!
That’s disgusting! Oh!
Oh, they’re doing
those dirty dishes.
Whew.
And mother is telling father
all about the things she did
while he was at work.
Well, I isolated
that nucleotide today.
The first thing
she did this morning
was to fix up the kitchen.
Mom leads a life
of quiet desperation.
She cleared the table
and washed the dishes
and put the food away
and made everything
spick and span.
While suppressing
her own dreams.
Then she went up to tommy’s room
to straighten it.
As she chokes back
the bile of resentment.
There were train tracks
and other toys
to be picked up
and put away.
There was the bed to be made.
And the maid to be bedded.
[Imitates rimshot]
There were clothes
to be hung up.
And some would need
washing or mending.
After that, mother started
on the ironing.
The most satisfying
part of her day.
Doing the family
washing and ironing
is a pretty hard job.
Mm.
But mother does it regularly
every week.
She’s in what we call a rut.
- And the cooking.
- Oh, yeah.
Mother has to find time
to make good, nourishing meals
for the whole family.
We’re having cat today.
[Imitates cat screeching]
Tommy’s appetite is getting
bigger and bigger.
While his brain
gets dimmer and dimmer.
Later, she did the mending.
There’s tommy’s cowboy shirt.
And his jacket.
He can rejoin
the village people now.
Tommy could be more careful
with his clothes.
Yeah, why should he?
Those are just
some of the things
that mother has to do.
No wonder she’s often tired
at the end of the day.
Tired of tommy.
It seems mother never stops
working for the family.
And the man.
And what about father?
What does he do all day?
Well, he had a particularly
hard job today.
Dad pulls the lever
at the big house.
[Imitates electricity crackling]
...but he did it anyway.
Because that’s the way father
earns money,
by doing the job.
A lousy job.
You see,
it is the time he gives,
the work he does,
that he gets money for.
Here. We gotta let you go.
Here’s your pink slip.
Be out of the building by 5:00.
Thanks a lot.
...and give tommy
his allowance too.
In a way, the money
is father’s work.
Hmm.
At home, before supper,
father worked
on the family budget.
Oh, man.
We’re in trouble.
It isn’t easy to figure out
how best to spend the money.
Because there are always
so many bills to pay
and so many things
the family wants to buy.
Luxuries like shoes and food.
After supper, father repaired
a broken chair.
Fixing things
instead of buying new ones
- is a good way to save money.
- Hmm.
Yes, sir, father and mother
do a good job
of working together.
Given their limited
capabilities.
Like a team.
Yeah, as for tommy,
he’s a slacker.
They do so many things
for the whole family.
And that’s something tommy
hadn’t thought about before.
A team.
I’ve got it.
I’m resolved now.
That’s what a family is.
A family is a team
that works together.
A losing team, but still--
and tommy would like
to be on that team.
So he punts a football
through the window.
He thinks it’s something
like a football team.
Yes, tommy likes
to pay on a team.
And he knows
that to have a good game
you must all work together.
And take steroids.
And every member of the team
must do his share.
Or have a rich dad.
Now tommy wants to do his share
for the family team.
One thing--
he can save his money.
Not ask father for more.
And so help the family
buy more things they all want.
And starting right now,
he can help mother
by putting things away.
Like his hopes and dreams.
Yes, from now on,
things are going
to be different with tommy.
Whoo! His feet stink.
Ugh.
After a week or so
of trying...
He gives up.
Tommy was really working
on the team.
When a piece
of train track was broken,
tommy fixed it himself...
Killing 400 commuters.
So father
didn’t have to fix it
or spend money
buying new track.
Don’t you think that’s
a good way to help your father
and show him how much
you appreciate
all he does for you?
If you’re into
that kinda thing.
And see how neat
tommy’s room is.
Tommy’s gotten in the habit
of picking things up
and putting them away.
And it makes him proud
when mother
doesn’t have to do any work
in his room.
Now that he’s in his place.
Isn’t that a good way
to help your mother
and show her how much
you appreciate
all she does for you?
My mother is a saint!
And tommy has thought
of other things
he can do for his parents.
Last night he did
a ring job on the car.
It’s really
more fun than work
when you know you’re helping
your mother and father?
You know, mom, i’m gonna be
a mixologist when I grow up.
Wouldn’t you like
to do things for your parents...
Mom, I translated
a beckett play this morning.
Then help to keep your room
clean and neat.
Well, seal it off.
Don’t go in there.
Keep your clothes on hangers.
Try not to tear them
or get them too dirty.
Try not to eat them.
Put things where they belong.
Don’t leave them on the floor
when you’re not using them.
Yeah, what is with you
today, tommy?
- Help save money.
- Mm-hmm.
Remember, someone
has to work to earn it.
Get porky some pants.
Help your parents
around the house.
There are many jobs
you can do
that will make things easier
for father and mother.
Tommy showers only half
his body to save water.
Try to think up new ways
you can help your family.
And ask your mother
and father about them.
Hmm.
They’ll be glad that you want...
- Aah!
- Ooh.
...how much you love them
and appreciate all the things
they do for you.
Aah! Nothing, dad.
Nothing. Nothing.
I was just...
...as tommy’s
father and mother do.
And what’s more,
because tommy
has helped us save money,
mother and father agree...
You do the voice.
I’ll work the jaw, honey.
Hello, bubbie.
A bigger allowance.
A nickel. Thanks, dad.
That’s mighty good.
But what’s better,
tommy knows
he’s a real member
of his family team.
From slacker to booster.
Thanks, tommy.
Thanks, dad.
You dope.
[Laughter]
Your body looks good.
This is the story
of a robot named crow.
Can you guess what crow
is thinking?
Crow is thinking hard,
or as hard
as he can think, anyway,
on how the satellite
got so darn clean.
It wasn’t clean this morning.
Think hard now, crow.
Think really hard,
you poor dope.
Scan that scrap heap
you call a brain
and try to find some
piteous shred of thought or--
hey, knock it off.
Oh, sorry.
[Clears throat]
Ah, yes. There it is.
Who does these things
when we’re too lazy,
too bloated on dinners
of rich food
and generous portions
of our own gargantuan ego?
Who debugs the massive
computer control center
because our own
enfeebled brains
can barely add fractions?
Who provides the warm,
inviting water
in which you bathe your filthy,
oil-stained carcass?
Who goes on mind-bendingly
dangerous missions
outside in the cold, black void
of unforgiving space
while you sit inside,
cozy as alistair cooke,
sipping cocoa and watching
tiny toons?
Pinch yourself hard,
mr. Robot.
You deserve it.
You think you’re all
sunshine and goodness,
but you’re nothing but dirt
between the toes
of an evil troll.
That’s right.
Who periodically changes
the plutonium rods
in the nuclear reactor
deep in the bowels of the ship
while you feast
on gooey handfuls
of fiddle faddle and play
hopscotch and marbles?
And it’s spring,
and the little--
hey, now just a dog-blasted
minute here.
What are you
laying it all on me for?
You’re the laziest robot
i’ve ever seen.
Oh, I see.
It’s me now, is it?
Too painful to look into that
deep, dark, truthful mirror, eh?
You make me sick.
I thought you looked sick,
but it’s always
hard to tell with you.
Why, I ought to--
uh, hi.
[Stammering]
Gypsy.
I gotta go clean my room.
I’m gonna go
clean your room too.
He’s gonna help me
clean my room.
Ooh.
Oh, the unearthly.
Huh?
Oh,
starring john carradine.
That was kung fu, right?
No, no, no, he was the guy
in revenge of the nerds.
Oh, isn’t he the guy that does
all those alan rudolph films?
Oh, that must be it.
He’s all of those and more.
Music by the edgar allen poe
marching band.
[Imitates music]
You know, I read
in video watchdog
that geoffrey dennis
completely rewrote
jane mann’s original script.
- She was really mad
about it, too.
- Oh, yeah, I read that too.
You know what I read
in starlog?
That robert a. Terry
had to be brought in
to smooth things over.
It was--
it was really a mess, man.
Did you read in fangoria
about how richard currier
and morton tubor
were at each other’s throats?
Yeah, they said the whole
shoot was a big ordeal,
and the three days
were absolute hell
of the whole thing, yeah.
Did you read in gorezone
about the torrid love affair
- between betty sinclair
and paul grancell?
- Oh, no.
Wait, why would their
love affair be in gorezone?
Have you seen betty?
- Oh!
- Ba-boom.
Y’know, I read in newsweek
that henry vars
really resented mitchell terr
supervising his music.
You read newsweek?
Ha. What a loser!
Hey.
Can’t believe it.
The fanzine sketch,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
[Dog barks]
Hey, your car’s barking.
Better change your bark plugs.
Ah-ha. Yeah.
Sky.
Cute.
[Dog barks]
What is this,
"dog on a hot tin roof"?
Hey, look. She’s dating
mr. Dithers from blondie.
Yeah, dagwood...
[Doorbell rings]
Hey, it’s tor johnson.
Avon calling.
Tell dr. Conway
that we’re here.
Loren.
Oh.
Good to see you.
Thank you, charles.
This is grace thomas,
the patient I phoned you about.
Oh, those--she’ll do nicely.
Pleased to meet you,
mrs. Thomas.
Dr. Wright has told me
a great deal about you.
And what you didn’t tell me
the photos will reveal.
Don’t say hi.
I’ll be up
to tuck you in later.
Ms. Thomas, i’d like you
to meet my assistant,
dr. Gilchrist.
I’m pleased to meet you,
ms. Thomas.
We’re delighted to have you
join us here.
We’ve been expecting you.
I have some things to do,
doctor.
Things?
- You’ll excuse me.
- Certainly.
Now should we make
ourselves comfortable?
Charles,
I finally convinced grace
that the best thing for her
would be to place
herself in your care,
and that with your help
her recovery here
would be a certainty.
Thank you, loren.
I’m sure we’ll do
everything possible
to make your stay here
pleasant and comfortable.
Your decision to come here
was indeed a wise one.
Oh, she’s anne sexton. Oh.
I’m sure I can.
To start with,
we’ll see that you get
plenty of fresh air, rest.
Then of course
my treatments.
I’m sure you’ll
benefited by them.
My dear,
you’re a very lucky girl.
Dr. Conway’s one of the finest
men in the field.
Oh, it’s nothing.
I really...
...that he has accepted
your case.
I’m very grateful.
If you don’t mind, doctor,
i’d like to show
ms. Thomas to her room.
- Sure.
- Come with me, grace.
I’ll see that you’re
comfortably settled.
Oh, uh, by the way, grace,
i’ll get in touch
with your father
and ask him to send you
the things that you need.
I’m sure he’ll
be most pleased...
More things?
Thank you.
Good night, grace.
Don’t fall off your shoes.
I’ll look in on you
before you retire.
Aah!
Dibs.
What’s this business
about her father?
No need to get excited,
charles.
Everything’s
been taking care of.
Our agreement was that
the patients you brought to me
were to have no relatives,
no ties whatsoever.
And I tell you that this one
has no ties.
Precisely,
what does that mean?
I ask you,
morton kondracke!
Grace thomas
committed suicide.
Committed suicide?
Someone should tell her.
Her bag and coat will be found
floating in the bay.
I think you’ll find
this room comfortable.
It has lots of things.
And don’t worry.
We have everything
you need right here
until your clothes arrive.
You’re very kind.
These things should fit you.
Oh, and there’s plenty
of bullet bras in the drawer.
You’ll find the other things
you want in the bath.
- It’s awfully good of you.
- Not at all.
Now i’ll be back later
and bring you some warm milk.
And we’ll give you
a little sedative.
Make you wake up rested.
To youth.
To eternity.
To ted kennedy.
What’s the word?
Thunderbird.
What’s the price?
40 twice.
Quite.
I’m more than anxious
to see your last experiment
on jedrow, charles.
Jedrow?
Very well.
Come with me.
I’ll show you.
We’ll be back with
"pons and fleischmann:
The early years"
- it’s al lewis.
- Hey.
Yeah.
Oh, it’s ann b. Davis.
Ugh.
Of course it’s jedrow.
[Quacking, grunting]
[Groans]
Thanks.
I needed an eye-opener.
No, thanks.
I don’t smoke.
This is how you throw
a knuckle ball.
I know phil niekro
is old, but whoa.
[Grunting]
[Imitates knocking]
Will he be all right?
I’m afraid not.
Perhaps you could
counteract the treatment?
Oh, that’s impossible.
Then what
are we going to do?
Wait. Wait and hope
that he comes out
of this state of shock.
[Continues grunting]
And if not?
[Grunts]
We continue
our experiments further.
Must have younger subjects.
Radiation must be
carefully calculated
in relation to the subject’s
age and metabolism.
[Grunting]
But isn’t it possible
to do something
stop giving him
burgess meredith injections.
Why are you so concerned
about him?
I’m afraid we’re in
a bit of difficulty.
What do you mean,
difficulty?
A relative of his showed up.
A relative?
Harry jedrow has a sister.
She’s been to my office
trying to locate him.
Her name’s elly may.
Jedrow never said anything
about a family.
I took it for granted.
You took it for granted.
In science,
nothing is taken for granted.
What are we going to do?
What’ll I tell his sister?
That, my dear fellow,
is your problem.
Wait in my office for me.
I’ve got to see grace.
Hey, uh, don’t forget
to turn the guy off.
Come in, lobo.
Uh, tor make bundt cake.
Go ahead.
Time for pedicure.
Let’s see.
Now what we’re gonna do
is take that gray out.
Uh, I see a more
chic look for you.
You’re just waiting to happen,
dear.
Kiss me. I’m irish.
Blue eye shadow is a no-no.
You have combination skin,
see?
So I mix up a little
oil of olay here.
Uh, let’s see.
You’re oily up here.
Dry here.
Dead here. Ooh.
That’s a definite no.
Oh. Hey. Check him out.
He’s doing his dangerfield.
Ah, no respect.
No respect.
Yeah,
don’t get any respect.
Stairway. Ho. It’s--ah.
Well, my dear,
you look radiant.
If I were rembrandt,
i’d paint a portrait of you.
Tell me.
You comfortable here?
I make a nice living.
I like it here very much.
Good.
Now tell me, my dear,
what seems
to be bothering you?
Uh, you’re sitting on my leg.
Don’t know, doctor.
I’m always so frightened.
Frightened of what, grace?
Carradines on my bed.
I’m just afraid.
Well, you mustn’t be afraid.
Not of anything.
Often I want to cry.
Just cry.
See this shoulder,
honey?
Any time.
It’s right here for you.
I have no one to turn to.
Now, now, my dear. From now on
that’ll all be different.
I want you to have absolute
confidence in me.
Trust me implicitly.
Come to me with your problems.
No matter what they are.
Come to me in a thin negligee.
Tonight I want you to have
a good night’s rest.
Tomorrow you’ll feel better.
Hey, john,
why the long face, pal?
[Laughter]
Bone structure.
Hey, john. You should check
those bags under your eyes.
Whoo! Hoo-hoo.
Affection, attention...
An old character actor.
You’re very kind to me,
doctor.
Oh, here comes the ref.
Not to discuss your affairs
with anyone but me.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, doctor.
Doctor wright is waiting for you
in your office.
Oh, thank you.
I almost forgot.
Goodnight.
I’ll see you in the morning.
Good night, doctor.
Mm-hmm. Hmm. Nice thing.
Thank you.
Well, would you like to sample
our anti-depressant cart?
Uh, we have
bleu cheese valium,
flintstones chewable prozac,
and william styron tablets.
Take these.
Hey, isn’t he the guy
from monopoly?
I’ve just looked in on grace.
She was in her jammies.
I don’t anticipate
any great difficulty
in getting her
straightened out.
Well, i’m glad, and I hope
she makes an excellent
subject for you.
The subject was roses.
I’ve given her the sedative.
Thank you, sharon.
I’ll be getting back to town.
Good night, sharon.
Good night, charles.
Good night, loren.
- Good night, john-boy.
- Good night, mccloud.
These must be grace’s.
- I’ll take them to her.
- What’s that?
I’ll take these to grace.
- No.
- What?
Let me have them.
That’s my purse.
Give me that.
Sit down.
We have to talk.
[Goofy humming]
Lauren.
You’re getting careless.
- You forgot these.
- Your parting gifts.
Well, I am sorry, charles.
I’ve given up
my alternate lifestyle.
- Good night.
What about my kiss?
- Oh.
- [Kisses]
Damn.
[Grunts]
Lights, please. Lights.
We need lights.
- What happened, bobo?
- Uh, I forgot.
I found him in the garden.
Can I keep him?
What were you doing there?
I’m a turnip.
I was trying to find my way
back to civilization.
I’ve been hitchhiking.
A guy dropped me off
in the middle of nowhere
and I got lost.
- You lie, joe.
- I don’t think so.
Look, mister, I know what you
got in the back of your mind,
but you’re wrong.
I didn’t come here
to steal anything.
Then why have you come here?
I told you. I got lost.
My car ran out of tire.
Uh...
You told me
a fabricated story
which wouldn’t
convince a child.
Tor bought it.
Oh, mr. Scott. You’re not
being very clever at all.
Scott?
Where’d you get that name?
My name’s houston.
Mark houston.
You’re frank scott,
killer and thief.
You got the wrong boy.
Are you sure?
I don’t think I have.
There was a detailed
description of you
in the police bulletin
this morning.
Uh, I got new headshots.
That’s it.
You’re wanted
for killing a man in a holdup.
You’re sick, mister.
You ought to see a doctor.
I happen to be a doctor.
- Oh, touche.
- Ouch.
You see,
last night’s paper
carried your story
in the front page.
Leather jacket,
about six feet tall.
All right,
I wear a leather jacket
and i’m not a midget.
So what?
So he won’t be booked
on the sullivan show.
Have a cigarette.
Thanks.
It’s a skin compass!
You seem to be a bit wobbly.
- I’m all right.
- I’m a weeble.
- I’ll stand.
- Sit down.
Hey, I wobble,
but we don’t sit down.
You must be out of your heads.
Why else would a man wander
20 miles from civilization.
I told you exactly
how it happened.
I hardly think so.
You know, I pity you.
This is a town without pity.
Doc, the last thing
I need right now is pity.
Let’s just call it a day, huh?
We’ll say it’s been charming
and i’ll be on my way.
Tor resent that.
Your persistence
is admirable,
but highly impractical.
I have no intention of
turning you over to the police.
Perhaps I don’t believe
in capital punishment.
Oh, I have a better idea.
I’m willing
to offer you sanctuary.
Here.
Sanctuary. For me?
Sanctuary!
Well, that’s real fine.
Except nobody
does something for nothing.
I’m happy you’ve decided
to be honest with me.
I haven’t decided a thing.
I’m just curious.
I’d really like to find out
what it is you want from me.
Perhaps some assistance.
I might easily use
a man like you.
I don’t follow you.
- You will, scott.
- After you read dianetics.
I suggest we both retire.
We take up the details of our
little bargain in the morning.
Now wait a minute.
I didn’t make any bargain.
Oh, yes, you have.
You made your bargain
when you pulled the trigger
and shot that man down.
I suggest
you keep that in mind.
You’re a killer, scott.
A hunted man.
Wow.
Take all the help you can get.
May mean the difference
between life and death.
Tor, buddy,
you can drop your eyebrows.
- Yeah.
- Ugh.
You got this pretty well
figured out, haven’t you?
I’m a scientist.
Thinking is my business.
Along with
applying for grants.
All right.
I guess you win.
I’m afraid it has to be right,
doesn’t it?
Take mr. Scott--
or mark houston,
if you want it that way.
Take him to his room.
See that he has
some other clothes.
He’ll take you to your room.
Yeah, I know.
Doc, i’m afraid
you’re a very clever man.
Thank you, mr. Houston.
Yeah, tor got new best buddy.
Come on, friend.
Ha. They make a lovely couple,
don’t they?
So round, so firm,
so fully packed.
It’s toasted.
Lsmft.
[Laughs]
Ah, this sure is good grub.
- Cold.
- I like my trix heated.
"Eat," he says.
"Food and nutrition
are important," he says.
Don’t start with me, george.
Stuck in a stinking joint
like this.
Six weeks of get up, go to bed,
do this, don’t do that,
walk here, sit there.
Sign, sign.
Everywhere a sign.
- They got me all caged up.
- No cable.
I’ve had a lot of time to think
since i’ve been here.
I’m telling you,
i’m gonna get out of here.
It’s about time you got here
with that toast.
Now maybe the eggs
won’t taste so bad.
Cold.
You can’t do anything right.
Why I ever married you,
I don’t know.
Aw, tor work hard.
Go on, get back
to the kitchen.
You make me nervous.
Tor feel unappreciated.
Why do you have
to pick on him like that?
He’s nice to you,
and you’re always on his back.
I’d like to break his neck.
But i’d need a forklift.
Look, put that book down,
will you, and listen to me.
How long do you think
the doc can keep me here?
- Listen to this.
- I don’t wanna listen
to nothing.
"Her hair fell free
and hung thick and soft..."
Oh, jacqueline susann.
"Suddenly he released her,
- and she slipped
from his strong arms."
- Oh, yeah.
[Imitating truman capote]
That’s not writing.
That’s typing.
It’s none of your business
what I read.
I don’t like you reading
when i’m talking to you.
No reason for you to throw
my books around either.
I’d like to take all these books
and throw ’em into a furnace.
Guys make a fortune
scribbling junk like that
and idiots like you
spend your life reading it.
Oh, you’re in a lousy mood.
It’s a lousy world.
So you fight everything
and everybody, right?
Yeah.
Do you know any other way?
- Morning.
- Wow. Hello.
Day in the life
of biosphere two.
I’m natalie andries.
Sourpuss over there
is danny green.
He’s wearing a chip
on his shoulder this morning,
but once you get used to him
he gets worse.
- Coffee?
- Yes, it is.
Yeah, thanks.
When did you get here?
Last night. Late.
You don’t know how glad I am
to see a new face around here.
If I had to put up with
smiley over there another day
I think i’d scream.
So scream.
[Screams]
I know that’s a little blunt,
but let’s face it.
We’re all in the same boat.
Yeah, that we are.
I really won’t know
what brought me here
until I talk to the doc
this morning.
What about you?
Oh, I guess
I was kinda run down.
- By a car.
- Just couldn’t
coordinate myself.
Sort of mixed up too.
But i’ve been here
four months,
and i’m in the pink.
That doctor
sure snapped me out of it.
I might be going home soon.
Home soon? Home to what?
You got nobody waiting for you.
You feel fine? Okay.
Don’t tell me about it.
I ain’t fine.
I ain’t fine at all.
That’s not a very nice way
to talk to a lady.
I don’t wanna talk
to that lady at all.
Keep her off my back.
And you keep off my back too.
I don’t wanna talk to nobody.
Whoa. Switch to decaf.
Nobody wants to hear what
you like and don’t like either,
but that doesn’t stop you
from complaining all the time.
Don’t listen.
Seems to me
you started all this.
What is this?
An o’neill play?
Crying out loud.
What you don’t like
don’t matter.
Doesn’t make any difference
what you don’t like.
I can say whatever I want
and to whoever I want.
Before you do anymore saying,
you better do some listening.
Ho, break it up, you two.
The only way we’ll do that
is if you start acting like
a man instead of a school kid.
Now you come waltzing in here
out of the clear blue sky
and act like a big wheel.
Well, listen, big wheel.
I ain’t having any, you hear?
I ain’t having any. Don’t act
like a big wheel with me.
Coming in...
[Whistling, applause]
Bravo. Bravo.
Does he get like that
very often?
Two or three times a day.
I don’t know what
gets him so steamed up.
Probably doesn’t know himself.
Poor dope.
Excuse me.
What about your coffee?
It’s cold.
Tortured by cold food.
Don’t do this.
Don’t do that.
He’s having his trouble again,
doctor.
Give him the usual amount
of r-16.
Yes, doctor.
Yeah. Do this.
Don’t do that.
Big shot.
Everybody’s a big shot.
Come on.
Hurry up with that, will ya?
Will you hurry up with that?
I’m burning up.
- Time to roll, guys.
- Oh, let’s go.
Hmm?
Oh, I get it.
He’s lenny bruce.
Oh, it’s just a case
of slight overacting, I think.
All right, dan.
You’ll be fine in a minute.
The unearthly? Man, they should
call it the un-acting.
YOU’RE RIGHT,
TV’s WISECRACKING CROW.
But, you know, at least
one of the cast members
is a decent actor who’s done
some good work in the past.
Exactly. John carradine.
That’s why i’ve prepared
this artists rendering
of his life and times in film.
[Groaning]
Come on. John carradine
made a lot of stuff.
He worked with john ford
in stagecoach.
He was in
drums along the mohawk.
He was the preacher
in the grapes of wrath.
Come on.
Joel, you’re missing the point.
We’re not talking
about john carradine.
We’re talking about tor johnson.
That’s right, and using
some advanced technology
called the video toaster,
we’re put together
a little presentation
that we like to call
the many faces of tor johnson.
Cambot,
give us a nice reveal there.
Yeah. Uh,
in the unearthly alone,
tor johnson runs
the gamut of emotion
from anger, to tenderness,
to bemusement,
and back to heartbreak.
There’s heartbreak.
Yeah. But you know,
the tor johnson canon
previous to the unearthly
displays the same versatility
that was the hallmark
of his acting career.
Why, here he is
in the title role
of the acclaimed film version
of king lear.
And here he is
as both felix and oscar
in the film version
of the odd couple.
But perhaps tor’s
greatest tour de force
was playing the multiple roles
in the tv remake of seven brides
for seven brothers.
Oh, whoa. Well, he’s never been
in a john ford movie.
Well,
as a matter of fact, joel,
he had one of the starring roles
in john ford’s
"she tor a yellow ribbon."
[Laughter]
Wow, i’m sorry
I even doubted you guys.
Never apologize, mister.
It’s a sign of weakness.
[Alarm buzzing]
Oh, we got movie sign!
I have discovered how to add
to the 16 existing glands
a 17th one,
artificially developed.
A new gland.
Oh, a designated gland.
What for?
This 17th gland is the secret
of youth and eternal life.
The promised gland.
With it, the aging process
can be arrested.
I can prolong life
for thousands of years,
perhaps forever.
Forever’s a long time, doc.
Yeah, tell us about it.
This movie’s a long time.
Yeah.
To be always exactly
as you are now.
To see the pageant of life
go by you
while you remain eternally
young and vigorous?
Carl jung?
Suppose you could
wake up every morning
and see your face
untouched by time.
Like dick clark?
Yes, you, mark. You.
You can be the first man
to have eternal life.
For three easy payments
of 19.95.
No, thanks, doc.
I’m happy just like I am.
Mark, to prove my theory,
I need a completely sound
human specimen.
Oh, well, i’m up for that.
Mentally and physically perfect.
You are that specimen.
That’s where you’re wrong.
The whole idea’s fantastic.
It’s crazy.
Why is it crazy? Because
it’s never been done before?
Because it can’t be bought
in a drugstore?
Yep, pretty much.
That’s it.
Pasteur, freud,
marie curie, ehrlich.
Westheimer!
I know my theory’s right.
I probed it.
Eternal life, mark.
- No, not for me, doc.
- I’m busy that week.
Like I said before,
i’ll stay just like I am.
And be burned
in the electric chair?
I’d rather do that than be
a guinea pig for you.
Mark,
this is not the first time
a condemned man’s life
has been offered to him
in return
for the progress of science.
I haven’t been
condemned yet, doc.
Perhaps not, but you’re
concerned about nothing.
I’ll take every precaution.
I’ll take the curtain.
Final process
will be tested and retested
before your final treatment.
Ah, I knew
there’d be a test.
So that’s what those
other people are here for.
Of course. They’re just rungs
in the ladder I have to climb.
In science, there’s always been
some necessary sacrifices.
Now you try saying that.
I don’t want any part of it.
No use talking anymore, doc.
I’m gonna get out of here.
Stop fighting
and give me skin.
I’m sorry our agreement
didn’t work out.
Shall I call the police now
to come and pick you up?
Oh, touche.
Wait a minute.
You tell the police about me,
i’ll have a few things
to tell ’em about you.
And who’ll believe you?
The house ethics committee.
...your word against mine.
You’re a hunted man.
I happen to be
a reputable scientist.
If you were to repeat
what I told you,
you wouldn’t have the proof
to substantiate your story.
You know, I think that’s
the visible venus de milo here.
What’s it going to be,
mark?
Shall I call the police,
subject us both
to a duel of wits?
A duel i’m bound to win?
Oh, let the baby
have his way.
No.
I’m glad you decided
to see it my way.
I don’t have much choice, do I?
Very sensible conclusion.
Now, you are not
to discuss or disclose
my conversation
or my plans in any way
to anyone at any time, anywhere.
Do you understand?
Why talk about something
nobody’d believe?
Don’t worry, doc.
I’ll keep my mouth shut.
Hey, hal is reading your lips.
Now we can start.
Old age will be conquered.
You’ll be here to accept
the acclaim of a grateful world.
Wait.
Who turned off the li--
huh? Oh.
Grace,
this is a wild book.
Here.
I want you to read it.
It’s jackie o
and lee radziwill.
Be seeing ya later, honey.
And now, our next
miss manic depressive event,
the swimsuit competition.
Morning.
I was hoping you’d show up.
I heard you were
a perfect specimen.
- Oh?
- Gonna be around later?
Well, I didn’t have
any other plans.
I have to see the doc
right now,
but that won’t take long.
Good. That case, i’ll see you
after a while, huh?
Bye.
- Grr.
- Down, boy.
[Growls]
[Dog barks]
Oh, that must be
ellen barkin.
- Ooh.
- I kill me.
Morning.
I resent that.
My name’s mark houston.
Mark houston.
And what’s yours?
What’s the matter?
Don’t you wanna talk to me?
Grace thomas.
Grace?
Pretty name
for a pretty girl.
You been here long, grace?
Yesterday.
Makes two of us.
I got here last night myself.
I didn’t think I was gonna like
it being so far from everything,
but now
it doesn’t seem so bad.
I’m a killer.
What’s your racket?
Nothing.
Well, how’d you happen
to come here?
My doctor brought me.
He said i’d get well here.
Welded?
You look fine. What’s supposed
to be wrong with you?
I like things.
I guess you could call it
a nervous breakdown.
My 19th.
He’s been very upset
and afraid.
- Afraid of what?
- Um, things.
I don’t know.
Well, sooner or later,
everybody’s afraid of something.
I’m afraid of sock monkeys.
Go figure.
But today it’s different.
Today, everything’s
right with the world.
I got a nice
place to stay,
plenty of fresh
air to breathe and, uh...
I’m taking the first step.
I wish it
were that easy for me.
What’s dr. Conway say?
Are they in the same scene
or what?
Why not?
Dr. Conway wouldn’t like it.
Tim conway?
No, I guess he wouldn’t.
Are you going
to be here long?
Yeah, it looks that way.
Hell,
i’m loonier than you are.
We’ll be seeing
a lot of each other.
That’ll be nice.
As long as we’re going
to be here for a while,
we ought to see what the place
looks like, hmm?
Can’t he see plenty
from right there?
Well, i’m supposed to rest.
You’ve been resting.
I guess it will be all right.
Nice scene, folks.
Very nice.
Just sign here.
Need your php card.
Hoiman, hoiman.
You get me out of this chair!
Itsy bitsy spider...
Mm-hmm.
Either he’s dead
or my watch has stopped.
Ba-boom.
Hey, she’s putting it
in warm water.
Oh.
Doctor,
I killed three minutes.
Good, good.
Did you check jedrow?
- Yes.
- Jethro?
Well?
Pulse normal,
heartbeat faint but regular.
Respiration steady,
reactions, none.
Wait a minute.
That’s me.
None.
You’ve handled
that perfectly.
We can’t check the reaction
until he emerges from
the catalatic state.
There should have been
some change by now.
Yes, I don’t understand.
Oh, how do I shave
a face this long?
We’ll just have to wait.
Can you suggest any further
treatment, charles?
- Anything further, father?
- [Imitates rimshot]
If we interrupt
the process now,
we won’t have
the information we want.
Oh, we’re all used to that
by now.
[Telephone rings]
My god, i’m impotent.
Hello?
1-9-7-6 gland.
It’s loren.
Oh.
Oh, hello, d.H.
How are you, loren?
I’m all right.
But jedrow’s sister...
Ha ha. Jethro wants
to be a rock star.
[Laughs]
Jedrow.
But she’s insisting to know
the whereabouts of her brother.
I don’t know
what to tell her.
[Humming]
I’m back.
Make out a death certificate
for harry jedrow.
Harry jedrow is dead.
Oh, but, charles.
He’s--
man, that guy
is good on that phone.
His technique--
ugh.
But he’s alive.
No, my dear.
Jedrow is dead.
Long live jedrow.
You might wanna go tell him.
It’s gonna be quite a shock.
Hi.
I was gonna say perky.
Oh.
Second the motion.
Sit down, natalie, and i’ll
tell him you’re here.
Nutcase natalie’s here.
Man, the doctor
lives in the same house
and you still
gotta wait an hour?
Yeah.
She’s nothing if not prompt.
And did I mention perky?
Mm. You did.
Well, I must say
you’re very prompt.
I was going to say "perky,"
but...
I dare say you’re wondering
why I had you come in here
this afternoon.
Well, I think I have some
very good news for you.
You’re a woman.
We’re certain of it.
During the last three months,
you’ve made tremendous strides.
In fact, your improvement
has been more than excellent.
I’m so happy, doctor.
[Whispers]
And perky.
Stop.
...i’ve never seen
such rapid progress.
Natalie, you’re almost
well enough to leave.
Oh, that’s wonderful.
When can I go home?
Oh, very soon.
Before I let you go, though,
there is one
final treatment necessary.
[Imitating
sensual funk music]
I’m sorry natalie missed this.
I wonder why
she wasn’t at dinner.
Maybe it was the bach.
So do I.
I’ll see if I can find out.
Boy, from one hot chick
to another.
Dinner’s over,
and he’s headed for dessert.
Don’t you enjoy
the doctor’s music?
Yeah.
That’s why i’m leaving.
Yeah, sure,
but we just finished dinner
and we missed natalie.
I thought i’d go upstairs
and see if she was all right.
Natalie asked for a tray
in her room this evening.
That’s a privilege
you all have.
[All imitating
baseball organ]
Hey. She’s still idling
on the couch.
She had a tray up in her room.
Is she all right.
I don’t know.
Uh, would you like to see
the desert tray?
Looks like tor johnson’s
going for the don johnson
look here.
Tor, don’t play with your food.
Uh, no, tor,
you got it backwards.
Take the tray,
leave the girl.
Bonk.
Oh, sorry, honey.
[Grunts]
Will you get the door
for tor?
Okay, i’ll just put you
on the seat.
If you don’t have to go,
that’s okay.
Just try once, okay?
Okay.
I’m sorry.
I can’t think of the ending.
I can’t think
of anything else.
A pretty girl...
Party girl?
Pretty...
Pretty girl.
- Wake up.
- Lobo.
It’s elvis costello.
Lobo.
I’m sorry.
Lobo’s not in right now,
but if you’d like
to leave a message...
Lobo, send them all to bed.
Lobo get yayas out.
Wait.
Who works his eyebrows?
He didn’t even cover her up.
Poor dear.
Tor want fats waller now.
Yeah.
One more time!
No.
Time for go to bed.
Well said.
Shall we retire?
Why? Are you coming apart?
Oh, that’s a different joke.
Oh.
[Imitates rimshot]
Good night, doctor.
Quit eyeballing my woman,
you rotten...
[Clock chimes]
Escher.
I like this more
than the organ, don’t you?
Oh, those shoulders.
So white, so...
Oh, this is gonna be great.
I can’t...
- Goodnight, mark.
- Goodnight?!
Night.
Looks like a real nice room
you got there.
Maybe I could come--
oh.
Shoot.
Door number one,
door number two,
let’s make a deal.
Oh, no, no.
It goes [imitates
"shave and a haircut."]
Not quite used to the place,
mark, huh?
We don’t knock in this house.
Your room is over here.
Oh, you see, I thought
that was my room...
[Laughing nervously]
Sorry.
- Thanks.
- For nothing.
Did you sterilize
my number 23 scalpel?
I got confused
and sterilized your cat.
This is the night, sharon.
- I’m certain of it.
- What?
After all the years
of preparation
and calculation, failures.
All pointing us
toward this operation.
And you mobile cattle
should rule out
any chance of
aborted variation.
It must, charles.
It will. We must succeed.
All right.
Administer the anesthetic.
Wait a minute.
He’s wearing playtex gloves.
So he can pick up a dame.
By that time, my lungs
were aching for--
oh, that’s your line.
I’m sorry.
Whoa. It smells
like lobo in here.
He must be having
a misadventure.
Hey, she got
two pieces of pie.
Ugh. I could use these
on my next robbery.
[Laughs]
Oh, she’s got
all the extras in here.
Luke, it is your destiny.
A briggs and stratton
breathalyzer.
Oh.
Hmm.
Scalpel.
Aah!
Pinking shears, pink thread,
elmer’s,
wood glue, and glitter.
Whoa! Suction. Whoa.
I got a bleeder here.
Whoa, look at it squirt.
Oh. I did that wrong.
Whoops.
Oh, yeah.
Keep those coming.
Keep them coming.
Ho, ho.
Clamp.
Clamp!
Wipe my brow.
Now kiss me hard.
Through the mask.
Clamp.
Sponge.
Box-end wrench.
Butterfly screw.
Number 23 scalpel.
Not the 23 scalpel.
You’re mad, doctor.
Ah, there we go. I’ll be
through her gown in no time.
Brow.
Now tell me i’m the best.
Sponge.
There. Got the bubbles.
The gland.
Hmm?
[Whispers]
The miracle gland.
Oh.
This is the most
wonderful scientif--
hey, wait a minute.
That’s an uncle josh’s
pork rind.
The bunny gland.
[Dramatic music]
Nice music.
Ugh.
This brown ’n serve is alive!
Alive!
All right.
Suture.
No, wait.
This thing looks delicious.
Butter. Log cabin.
Yeah, we should really
put scuzzy port in here
while we’re at it.
Yep.
[Sniffs]
It smells like an open gland.
[Knocks]
Yes?
- It’s mark.
- Are you cooking in there?
Open the door, grace.
I’ve got to see you.
Wait. Let me wrap myself
in gauze.
What is it?
I wanna get you away
from this house.
Oh, how many times
has she heard that?
Danger? Why?
Dr. Conway isn’t the kind
of a man you think he is.
He’s an elf.
I don’t understand.
I just checked
natalie’s room.
Her clothes are all there,
but she’s gone.
She’s been gone
for quite a while.
I don’t like it, grace.
Conway’s a madman.
I’m afraid he’s done
something to her.
How can you say that?
Well, that could
have gone better.
I’m really out of practice.
What?
In eight hours
we’ll know the answer.
What do you say
we go to the swamp
and have cocktails.
Grace, he’s got
some fantastic idea
he can work miracles
to keep people young forever.
It’s called porcelana.
He actually told me he wants
to use us as guinea pigs.
He’s even been talking
about sacrifices for science.
Now with a mind that warped,
there’s no telling
what he’s thinking.
I won’t believe that.
The doctor’s trying to help me.
To help myself.
I can’t accept
what you’re saying, mark.
You’ve got to accept it.
Your whole life depends on it.
Look, first thing
in the morning,
I want you to go and see conway
and get your release.
I don’t care
what you tell him,
but somehow convince him
you have to go home.
I’m here under
my own doctor’s advice.
Your doctor’s
claus von bulow.
Don’t you understand?
You have to get out
of this house
before it’s too late.
You’d better
get out of this room
before doctor conway
finds you here.
I don’t think he’d approve.
Grace--
i’m going to call
the house mother.
Strange place
for a hummingbird feeder.
Get some duct tape.
Thing on. This thing on.
That thing.
Then that other thing on.
Okay, let’s see.
Garage lights on,
kitchen lights on.
Ready.
[Sustained tone]
Oh, they turned on
the emergency broadcast system.
Hmm.
14.
- 26.
- Skidoo!
50%.
Eight acres.
- Reading?
- 12 hectares.
26 1/4.
One cubit.
50%.
- Hut, hut.
- 50%.
- Reading?
- Plus 2.4.
Increase 2%.
A quart of 2%.
- Increase 2%.
- Reading?
- Plus 2.48.
- Minus three.
Increase slowly to 55.
Is he reading poetry again?
He’s making it up
as he goes along.
I think so.
Hey.
- Ten.
- Are we not men?
- Nine.
- A bajillion.
- Eight.
- 20. - 50%.
- Seven.
- Eleven.
Avogadro’s number.
Boogah, boogah,
boogah, boogah.
Newman!
Five...four...
Booger.
Three...two...one...
Zero!
Ooh, it’s great!
Huh?
Mom?
What’s all the racket?
[Groaning]
Her thermometer popped up.
She’s done.
Oh. She’s delicious.
Oh, great. They’ve moved
the movie into the basement.
They’re really reaching now.
Here in the wine cellars
of ernest and julio gallo--
all the best.
Uh, this’ll be
the boys room over here.
Eight hours on the dot.
Well, goodnight.
This is it.
Uh-huh. Now let’s, uh--
hmm.
Door’s kinda tough.
It, uh, oh, see?
It pulls out.
I’m sorry.
Oh, crap. Again?
- Ugh.
- No.
No, it can’t be.
Yes, it can.
- Ew.
- Ick.
Oh, no.
She looks like me.
How could this have happened?
I took every precaution.
I washed my hands--
medical school.
That’s it. Medical school.
Cripes. I’ve turned her
into a sleestak!
Put that side
against the wall.
Well, dear,
i’ve got some bad news.
Your modeling career
is down the toilet.
Ugh.
[Nervous laugh]
Uh, mind if I skip dinner?
I’m a bit off my food.
Well, may I say
how sorry I am
and small mistake
with your chart.
Uh, look on the bright side.
Ugh.
Don’t be discouraged, charles.
You’ll succeed.
All these years
of study and hard work
can’t go unrewarded.
Yeah. Sure. Whatever.
Ick.
Ugh.
[Door opens]
Good morning, grace, mark.
Good morning, doctor.
Doc.
I’m going on upstairs.
Paul bunyan,
where’s your blue ox?
Will you come into
the common room, my dear?
I’d like to talk to you.
Nice.
My dear, you’re to be
congratulated.
Your condition has improved.
If you continue
in this manner,
you’ll be entirely well
in no time.
I hope so.
Come and sit down.
Ethan allen.
Tell me, grace...
Do you care
how your skin looks?
Look out for the snack bowl!
Oh.
What does a young couple
talk about
when they walk
in the garden?
I’m afraid a little
too old to remember.
Many things.
Mostly about natalie.
Really?
Well, what about her?
Mark seems worried
about her.
Why?
He seems to think
she’s ill or something.
Nonsense, my dear.
She made a perfect recovery
and I released her.
I drove her to the train
this morning myself.
She left rather early,
so she asked me
to make her goodbyes.
I’m so happy for her.
She looks like
irene ryan, but...
Grace, you’ve made
such fine progress.
I’d hate to have anything
stand in your way.
Look, john,
just pick a seat and sit down.
...limit your association
with mark.
Why?
Well, no matter
how I phrase it,
it’ll sound harsh
to you, but...
I’m a nazi.
Ooh, that does sound harsh,
doesn’t it?
Dangerous?
Yes.
Very dangerous.
There’s no telling
what he might do.
I don’t understand.
My dear.
Yeah, come on.
Scooch over.
Yeah. That’s better.
Oh, just get it over with
and sit on my lap.
He’s suffering an advanced
persecution complex.
Any incident might provoke him
into committing
an act of violence.
I’m watching him carefully
and trying to help him.
Bet his breath is terrible.
How can I help?
By avoiding
any unnecessary conversation.
Then he’ll be free
of any entangling emotions
which might harm him.
I’ll do as you ask, doctor.
Good.
We must look
after you too, doctor.
You’re so good to me,
dr. Conway.
I’ll scratch your eyes out.
[Hisses]
One so lovely as you
should have the understanding
and protection of a friend.
But above all,
you must disregard anything
mark may tell you.
I understand, doctor.
Now, i’m just going
to sit on the ottoman,
then i’ll be done.
I’m glad others think for me.
Just a little bit nervous.
Little bit jumpy.
Light. Light. Please.
He looks like the cat
that ate the canary.
Here. Use my ronson.
Works every time.
[Coughs]
Oh, and she just
puts it out.
What’s the point of that?
Leave that girl alone.
What does that mean?
Grace. Leave her alone.
You’re sounding
like a jealous woman.
That’s exactly what I am,
charles.
I love you.
And i’m not gonna have anything
come between us.
- Sharon.
- This is new.
Sharon,
two people striving
for such a great scientific
achievement
should not be quarreling.
Nothing should ever
come between us.
Except my hand puppet.
Charles.
Yes?
Why can’t she be
our next subject?
She’s almost
a perfect specimen,
and you said we needed
a good subject
for our next experiment.
- Not yet.
- Why not?
It isn’t the right time.
But be assured,
when the time comes,
I shall not hesitate.
Okay, right time now?
Is it time yet?
Now let’s join our friends
in another part
of the house.
[Suspenseful music]
Slow, slow, plink, plink.
Slow.
My dinner with andre
had more locations
than this film.
Nice rec room.
No way. Foosball.
They got everything.
Wow. Bumper pool.
Adolph hitler on vibes.
♪ Do do ♪
Slow, slow, plink, plink.
A sub basement.
I could put a workshop
down here.
You know, as long as
i’m down here,
- i’ll bring up
some corn relish.
- Oh yeah.
Maybe some of that
bread and butter pickle stuff
and watermelon rind pickles.
Oh, I love those.
Those are really good.
And some
pickled eggs, maybe.
Mrs. Bates?
- Mrs. Bates?
- Norman?
You know, I think he’s looking
for dave lennox.
Oh, of course,
that would follow.
Looks kind of like
david janssen.
Rah, can’t get
the door open.
Oh, sam, you’re in there.
Hmm.
Well, I had one of these
when I was a kid.
It’s a grandpa, I think.
D’ah, herman,
turn the light off.
I’m resting.
[Servo mimics penguin]
Man, those minnesotans
are so stoic.
Well, I thought
that would scare me
a lot worse than it did.
I was pretty cool
through that.
I’ll probably
have bad dreams.
Well...
Oh, good thing there’s
a dissolve in the staircase.
Makes it easier.
[Servo hums]
Uh, we knock in this movie.
What do you want?
- Two guesses.
- I’m sorry to
break in like this
but it’s my
only chance to prove
- i’m telling you the truth.
- Please get out.
But you don’t understand
i’m trying to help you?
Look, i’ve got
positive proof.
Proof you’ll
have to believe.
Please leave me alone.
Look, I don’t have time
to argue with you.
Here, put on this robe
and come with me.
♪ While strolling
through park one day ♪
Before this night’s over,
you’re gonna be
convinced i’m right.
[Crow sighs]
What is this, a three stooges
all of a sudden?
[Servo mimics moe howard]
There was a man here
not ten minutes ago.
Mark, please take me
back upstairs.
I tell you,
he was right here.
Mark, this is
getting boring.
- Mark, please.
- No, grace.
Not until we find that guy.
Cover your shame.
Oh, you know, I do love
these fanta-suites.
Say, are we in the jungle room
or the tarzan room?
Well, you gotta admit,
it’s really creepy down here.
Creepy creepy.
Creeparelly.
Creeparoony.
Creepa-deepa-deep.
Oh-- ew.
Natalie! It’s natalie!
Sissy spacek!
Wow, now I really am
hotter than her.
Yeah, that’s natalie.
- Natalie weird.
- It’s horrible.
- [Natalie groans]
- She’s been jerked.
Easy now, you’ve gotta
take a hold of yourself.
[Sobs]
I’m sorry you had
to see her like this,
but now maybe
you’ll believe me.
- How could he?
- Well, ’cause he had some
extra mozzarella lying
around, you know?
[Servo chuckles]
Gonna make some garlic face.
Ew.
Yeah, uh, close the door.
It’ll keep her fresh.
At least keep the odor in.
Whoo.
Oh, i’m really tired.
Good night.
- [Servo snores]
- Oh, natalie!
Grace.
Grace, we haven’t time
to think about that now.
We’ve gotta figure some way
to get you out of this house.
- How about the front door?
- Hey...
- I’m so afraid.
- I know.
Now, listen.
When I go out of this room,
you lock the door and don’t
open it for anybody
until I get back--
you understand? Not for anybody.
I won’t, mark.
- Okay.
- I’ll look like me.
Oh, we’d better go.
- Lock the door.
- Lock your car,
take your keys.
[Servo hums]
What in the-- oh, you guys.
- We’re zany.
- Which results in creativity.
Yeah, we thought
we could shake off
our own cabin fever
by playing a little game.
Yeah, but most of our games
are missing their pieces.
So we combined them
to make our own game
based on this week’s movie.
Wanna help us play a game?
Sure, what can I do?
Well, we’re all set up.
You could read the directions.
Oh, these? Okay. All right.
Oh, I can tell
you guys put these--
it’s kind of an amalgam of
a bunch of different
instructions.
Okay, got you.
Equipment-- game board
showing the many rooms
of john carradine’s
unearthly mansion.
- Did that.
- Looks good.
- All done.
Okay, each player chooses
a color, token, or marker.
Oh-oh-oh, i’m the shoe!
I’m always the shoe.
- Dibs on the shoe.
- Okay, you’re the shoe.
I get the iron, I don’t
want the pig this time.
- Okay, you’re the iron.
- Ah, lucky iron.
And i’ll be playing
my captain kirk king
from my franklin mint
collection chess set.
- Oh, I forgot about that one.
- The only piece you got.
Okay, what’s next? Uh...
Firsties, we roll
for firsties.
Okay, right.
Each player rolls the dice
in the tor johnson
pop-o-matic.
After the first player
has been selected,
but before you remove
his pituitary gland,
the player to his or her left
loses one turn
and then precedes to go.
[Talk over each other]
Each player starts out
with a billion dollars
and half a dozen hotels.
But immediately loses them
when they dump ivana
for marla.
Yeah, okay, okay,
let’s go, let’s go.
The player landing
on a plot stopper square
must go back to the beginning
of the movie
or play the organ
for five minutes.
All players must stay within
the boundaries of the house.
Players going
outside the house
or in any way suggesting
another location
put the film over budget
and must forfeit one turn
and pay the player
to his or her right.
The sum not equal
to net points made
- on the back end of the deal.
- Okay, we know!
Okay! Let’s roll! Roll!
Here we go! Pop-o-matic!
No, hold on, players caught
on the stairway
lose one turn.
- Uh-huh?
- Players caught in
a meaningless two-shot
with john carradine
lose one turn.
- Players who lose one turn--
- [all] Lose one turn.
- Okay! Here we go!
- [Talk over each other]
Wait a second-- players who
lose the breakfast argument
with the palooka advance
to the woman’s bedroom.
Palookas making advances
on the woman lose one turn.
Thank you, joel
you know, we wrote these rules,
so we know them.
We can just get to them
- as we go, so let’s go!
- Okay, hold on--
- dialogue cards.
- Aw, this is gonna
take ten minutes.
Players landing
on the dialogue box
must draw one card.
Players must then
read a passage of dialogue.
Yeah, but you don’t need
to do that, ’cause--
let’s do that
when we get to it--
- we’ll land on that square--
- it’s gonna be a half hour.
All right, okay, hold on.
Here it is. Here we go.
As john carradine.
Let’s see here.
I’m glad to hear
you’re willing to help.
You’re a clever young man.
I’ve decided you can be
of assistance to me.
- Pretty good carradine.
- Yeah.
I’m real handy to have around,
especially if you need
someone to bandage
a gunshot wound.
- John carradine.
- Okay, game-time.
- Joel.
That’s not exactly
what I had in mind.
Joel, come on,
we wanna play!
- --That we’d have
a little talk--
- hey, joel,
the commercial sign light
is flashing.
- You talk and i’ll--
- let’s just play the game!
What could be so wrong
with just--
oh, let’s just leave.
--To a project that most
scientists have considered--
please, mister,
can we have our ball back?
Beyond the realm
of possibility.
Believe me,
it’s not impossible
to the true scientist.
Hey, why didn’t
you guys wait?
’cause you were just
reading directions.
Hmm, missing
a balustrade there.
Tor like new lunch box.
Tor’s wearing
a wooden kimono.
Hey.
Hey, tor, how come
you’re coffin so bad?
- [Bots laugh]
- Nudge nudge.
That’s a great-- ahh.
I love that.
Tor deep into recycling.
Tisket, tasket.
Green yellow casket!
Pun!
[Servo chuckles]
Did I just see
a casket go by?
Hey, I can’t believe it--
they’re outside!
- Yep.
- Whoa. Whoa!
Under the spreading
chestnut tree,
the village smithy stands.
He’s wearing birki’s!
[Crow groans]
Mulch good for garden.
- Rich compost.
- D’uh, one.
D’uh, two.
I don’t like
this place, see?
Yeah, gives me
the creeps, see?
Yeah, this place
gives me the willies.
- I’m gonna blow!
- [Dog barks]
Uh, two-- oh,
dog make me lose count.
♪ Mr. Lobo risin’ ♪
[Servo mimics guitar]
[Dog barks]
[Crow mimics
popeye chuckle]
He didn’t notice me’ska.
Huh, i’ll just go out
and finish his jobsk for him.
Yeah, he won’t know
who did it, then.
Yeah, back off, you mutt.
D’ah, kitty!
[Dog whines]
Sit.
[Servo hums score]
Hey, abe vigoda!
Yeah.
I’m feeling much better.
[Servo gasps]
Well, what do you know?
I am ann b. Davis.
That sure was swell.
Man, this joint has class.
Yeah.
D’ah, back to work.
Uh...
Uh, one.
D’uh, two.
Alas, poor yorick.
I knew him, horatio.
D’uh, two.
This is what happens
when you sign
- with william morris.
- Two.
Man, this is the life.
[Knock on door]
- Who is it?
- Mark. Open up.
- It’s john "bowzer" bauman.
- Yeah.
Why-- why,
I oughta pop you one!
- What do you want?
Danny, let’s get
one thing straight.
- I didn’t come here--
- you muttonhead.
You’re in a jam, and I wanna
get you out of it.
- Give me the straight poop.
- I don’t need any help.
- Yes, you do,
now listen to me.
- Yeah,
what’s with the grabbin’?
What gives?
--Crazy experiments here.
He plans to use
- all of us as guinea pigs.
- You’re cockeyed!
I don’t believe it.
All right, don’t.
But stop and think, danny.
For once, really think.
What’s become of natalie?
Where is she?
Ah, you’re loco,
you’re screwy!
Now, if I had time,
i’d take you downstairs.
And show you-- i’ve seen her.
She’s in the cellar,
and i’ve seen what
conway’s done to her.
He’s turned her into a--
well, a god-knows-what.
She’s all twisted.
Her face looks like something
out of a nightmare.
Yeah, real sad-sack,
you know?
Why would he do
a thing like that to natalie?
- He’s a made man.
- Who knows why?
Nothing matters to conway
but his crazy ideas.
- And believe me, danny--
- he’s hoodoo, I tell ya!
--Only a sample of what
he’ll do to you, me,
or anybody else
he gets his hands on.
Yeah, yeah, he’s rotten.
- All right.
- Come on, let’s blow.
All right, well,
what can we do about it?
You can save your neck--
you can get out of this house
before it’s too late.
Before conway turns you
into some kind
of a horrible freak.
- How?
- Skip the patter
and grab your skivvies.
- I’ve already tried.
- I know.
But don’t worry about that.
You do what I tell you,
- you’ll get out all right.
- Yeah, just talk fast, see?
It’s 12:45.
You go to bed
and pretend you’re asleep.
At exactly 2:00,
you come downstairs.
Grace and i’ll
meet you there.
Yeah, sure thing, shut-eye.
That’s the ticket.
Okay. 2:00. I’ll be there.
Jake, i’ll hit the sack
and catch some z’s.
- You be on time.
- Yeah yeah, i’ll be there.
You know, stamps are fun.
Hmm, who’s playing
my hammond?
Huh, faucet’s dripping.
You’re not about to start
knocking again, are you?
Yeah, i’ll make like
i’m sawin’ logs.
[Joel snores]
He even sleeps crabby.
Chris isaak!
♪♪ [Servo mimics isaak]
Uh, nothing, dear.
Just checking the joists.
Okay, watch the lady.
We’re gonna
switch ’em around.
Watch!
Kinda high
for a bathtub drain.
Mm-hmm.
[Crow as basil fawlty]
Manuel? Polly?
Man, stairs.
This movie would’ve been
a lot shorter
if they filmed it
in a rambler.
Mm-hmm.
He should just
drink a glass of milk
- and go to bed.
- Yeah.
♪ Take sominex tonight
and see... ♪
Somebody’s knocking again--
I hate that.
Look, he’s more confused
than we are.
I gotta back up
and read the script.
Man, it’s like vaudeville
in slow-motion.
Well, let’s see, scene 13--
oh, let’s stop for the day.
I’m pooped.
- [All gasp]
- Don’t do that!
I’m a horror movie,
and you sneak up on me!
Have you just
been downstairs?
No, i’ve been in my room, why?
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
Is there something
wrong, charles?
Someone stole
the strawberries.
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Charles, i’m worried about you.
You’ve been working too hard.
Look at the collar
on anne boleyn, here.
Yes, please leave me alone.
Why don’t you
try to get some rest?
- You’ll feel so much better.
- And we can film it.
Perhaps you’d like
a glass of warm milk.
I’m not a child.
I won’t be pampered
or mothered.
I’d like strawberry quik
and some cookies, though.
I need nothing that
I do not wish to need.
Good night, sharon.
You wanna unpack that one
for us, grandpa?
Where’s that mug?
It’s blacker than
a parson’s hat down here.
Jeepers.
Yeah, keep that mug of shine
if you don’t show.
And the dolly, man,
she was poured into that dress.
I tire of gutter lingo.
- Hmm.
- What time is it?
Huh, must be almost time
for his meds.
Hey, it’s the stiff
and his dolly.
Yeah.
Good boy, danny.
Now, listen, you and grace
take the main road into town.
Remember, stay in the shadows
till you’re clear of the house.
I’ll take the low road
and be in scotland before you.
- --To move
as fast as you can.
- What about you, mark?
Well, i’ll make sure
conway doesn’t follow.
- I’ll catch up to you later.
- You sure you’ll be okay?
Yeah, yeah, i’ll be fine.
Now, get out of here.
- Oh, and danny?
- Yeah?
- Take good care of her, huh?
- Yeah, okay.
Yeah, she’s a real sweet kid,
you know?
D’oh.
- Well.
- So, a make-out party?
How come i’m not invited?
--Repay my hospitality?
Lobo? Sharon? Thank you.
- No, thank you.
- Oh no, thank you.
Oh, no thank you--
would you just?!
--Very clever,
but I can’t enjoy
watching my
kindnesses abused.
I suppose I should’ve
turned you over
to the police
in the first place.
Would it surprise you all
to know
that mark is
an escaped killer?
And a thief to whom
I offered sanctuary?
- That wouldn’t surprise me.
- It’s true.
And as for you, esmeralda--
the fact that
you turned against me
is the greatest shock of all.
That could’ve been
a convincing story, doc,
but now it’s too late.
Hey, it’s bob and carol
and tor and alice.
Take them away.
Downstairs, lobo.
Sharon, see that they’re secure,
and then join me upstairs.
Hey, baldy, get the gat
outta my backside.
Not you, my dear.
I have something special
planned for you.
Upstairs.
Slowly, walk real slow.
That’s it.
Hey, we’re watching
down by law all of a sudden.
Keep them here till I come back.
Understand?
Yes, I keep them here
till they get back.
Danny, take a look at this.
♪ Take a look
at these hands ♪
Night, mother.
Oh, ick.
Thanks for showing me that.
Follow my play.
I’ve got an idea.
Watch yourself.
Sure thing--
time for the old dipsy-doodle.
Routine 55.
Seen the sleeping beauty
in there?
You know, just like
in the storybook.
With a girl who’s real pretty,
- like natalie.
- Yeah, real attractive gal.
Put her into a dress, yeah.
She had a spell put on her by
this giant in a castle.
- Uh-huh?
- A giant?
Now, this giant,
he’s got a bull.
And the bull’s name
is ferdinand.
Ferdinand?
- Yeah--
- tor’s hooked on phonics!
--He doesn’t like
the beautiful red cape
that the giant has.
So he tries to get it.
But the giant,
he just takes the cape,
and he waves it
right in front of the bull.
Oh, he’s a tor-eador.
D’oh!
And he rushes
right at the cape.
The giant,
he just takes the cape,
- he throws it over the bull!
- Wait!
Do other voices.
Oh.
You know, that story’s got
a better plot than this movie.
Yeah.
Oh, no wound, huh?
Hey, we need a wound--
make-up!
Wait, wait,
don’t leave tor hanging.
What happens to ferdinand?
- Extraordinary.
- Yeah, all right.
Go ahead, i’ll follow you.
Are you sure
you can make it alone?
Yeah, yeah, sure, i’m swell.
Now scram!
Oh-- ow.
She’s well under.
Prepare her.
Hey, they’re gonna give her
a nose like latoya.
Say.
You mean, like michael.
What’s the dif?
Stay right there, conway.
You think that gun
is really necessary?
Yeah, finishes the ensemble.
--Much easier if
you put the gun away.
Maybe so, but you keep
your hands on top of the desk.
Very well, mark.
Wait a minute--
pretty girl, young girl,
old man, man with a gun!
The situation seems
to have altered slightly.
More than slightly.
I’ve got the gun.
Warm gun. Makes me happy.
--How long do you think
you could go on
destroying people
before somebody stopped you?
Oh, I don’t know.
20, 30 years?
--This from you, a killer.
A man hunted by the police.
I was about to give the world
the gift of eternal life.
Teach the world to sing
in perfect harmony!
--Mutilated
innocent human beings
you transformed them into
creatures so hideous
- they’d be better off dead?
- Oui. I did zat.
Who are you to question
the usefulness
of my experiments
in relation to the future?
Who are you to judge?
I was in
stagecoach and
grapes of wrath!
A happy world
about to thrown open
to a humanity
that wouldn’t die.
And not you or anyone else
can stop me.
Save that for the jury.
Ah, save it for
the final scene.
- Oh, but of course.
- You’re a bailiff.
I must admit,
you took me in completely.
A policeman.
I never thought.
You weren’t supposed to.
Let’s go.
No, I suppose
I have no choice.
Now, how often are you gonna
need a button like that?
Well, I got
an espresso machine.
I don’t use it much,
but it’s nice to have.
You got a point there.
Oh, now where’d he get
his flashlight?
For cryin’ out loud.
A four track,
a waffle iron, and sausages?
They’re recording breakfast?
[Servo yawns]
Get me the sheriff’s
office, quick.
There’s an outside.
Hello, casey,
this is a code three.
- Lieutenant houston.
- Jim? Jim-- jimmy?
Put your mother on-- no-no,
don’t hang up, jimmy, no!
Yeah, they know where I am.
Now get ’em rolling!
I’m gonna elope with myself.
I love me.
[Servo hums with score]
Van damme and van damme
in van damme yankees!
Ooh.
[Crow hums]
It’s confuse-o-vision again.
Whoo. It’s working.
♪ There’s a scientist
on a spree ♪
♪ and he’s skinny
as can be ♪
Oh, nuts!
Lobo has the keys!
Oh, go on inside
and get a coat hanger.
Come on.
I have no idea where
any of these people are.
What’s going on?
One adam twelve.
Movie needs resuscitation,
see the movie.
- Reagan!
- Yeah.
What’s the pitch, mark?
It’s conway.
He was out there somewhere.
I lost him.
- No one outside.
- We’d better split up.
- Kennedy, you go that way.
- And stay off the sauce!
I’m gonna check that house.
All right, good deal.
Come on-- let’s go.
Come on, otis,
you know how to do that.
Otis, come on.
Ah, well, there’s, um...
Ah, the key to the plot.
Why is that mirror
at belly-button level?
It’s a navel-gazer.
No.
You’re dead.
Herman! I’m not dead...
[Servo mumbles]
Well, thank you,
I didn’t get you anything.
I know you’re dead.
I told everybody.
Uh-oh.
That’s for the bach.
[Deflating sound]
Dying is easy.
Comedy is hard.
I’ll say.
Let’s dance, i’ll lead.
Dip-- oops.
Blame it on the bossa nova.
Lobo.
Uh...
Reagan.
Well, it looks like
somebody saved this--
yeah, bring in the meat bag.
Put this palooka
in the chiller.
Who’s this guy?
Fella named jedrow.
Conway tried
to bury him alive.
You know, it’s ironic.
I pulled him out of his grave,
and he ends up like this.
I can sense the irony.
Well, and this is
conway’s assistant.
Yeah, the milkman found her.
--What did you do
with ms. Thomas?
She’s in the lab.
George,
get the cuffs on him.
Captain, you’d better
come down to the cellar.
- No!
- No, no, not the cellar.
--You’d never believe it.
Okay, let’s go.
Wipe that chocolate milk
off your lip.
My, oh my, what a--
oh, forget it.
Grace?
Grace, wake up.
Come on.
Snap out of it now,
come on.
Grace before every meal.
Amen!
Oh, it’s a test pattern.
They temporarily
lost their signal.
Listen, it’s all right.
Everything’s all right now.
There’s nothing more
to worry about.
Sleep!
Oops.
I’ve checked him.
He’s dead.
This way, sir.
See, there’s one in here.
And then I found
another one in here.
This place is just
crawling with stuff
you wouldn’t believe.
Take a deep breath.
[Screams, grunts]
Hey, there’s another
movie in here.
Oh, it’s the cast
for quest for fire.
They saved
the best for last.
Wow, brian bosworth
and ben davidson!
Ian anderson-- aqualung!
- Oh.
- Wow.
Doctor, what’re
we gonna do with them?
Get michael jackson
on the phone.
He may wanna buy
one of these guys.
Well, it’s a good thing
we have institutions
that can take good care of them
for the rest of their lives.
The birth of the
world wrestling federation.
Okay, so who
mucks out the cages?
- [Creature snorts]
- Ew.
- Who?
- Good lord.
- Light a match.
- Yeah, really.
- --If they do live forever?
Uh, let’s just pretend
we didn’t see this.
Think of the paperwork.
That smelled like
a monkey house,
and then I knew for sure
that it was-- oh.
Lieutenant, who is this?
My new gal!
- Lieutenant?
- Captain reagan,
this is ms. Grace thomas.
She was one of conway’s
patients.
Grace thomas?
How glad I am to see you,
young lady.
You had us dragging the bay
for two days.
We almost had you
marked off as a suicide.
- Suicide?
- Yeah.
That’s a good way
to explain her disappearance.
Captain, you’d better
get at a pickup
- on a dr. Loren wright.
- Got my own pickup right here.
--Brought the others, too.
Yeah, i’ll get out
a call right away.
Come on, miller,
we have a lot of work to do.
Life’s funny, huh?
Lieutenant houston?
- Mark.
- Oh, lieutenant mark.
Will you please
take me home?
Yeah. Yeah,
of course I will.
That’s part of my job.
I see.
- Hey.
- [Servo smooches]
- How about breakfast?
Should I call you
or just roll over
and nudge you?
Hi, i-- [muffled voice]
- He’s off the ramp.
We have lift-off!
- Let’s go! Let’s go!
- Whoo!
- Yes! Brought to you
by the people
of cartoon-house.
Holy buckets,
what a cock-and-bull
hoodoo picture show
that was, eh fellas?
Boy, those old moss-backs
give me the jim-jam
somethin’ awful.
Yeah, i’d give that
honk up the nixie,
but hey, we’re really
footin’ it on the lingo.
Yeah, we can chip peg away
with a peddler’s french,
eh pal of mine?
Yeah, we’re goin’ hi-hat
in a big way, fellas.
- Hot, sweet, and filthy!
- Yeah, okay.
Now zip it,
you muttonheads.
We got a bug-letter
to sling.
Man, ain’t that jake!
Yeah, let’s put it--
boost it, cambot, okay?
Hoo, okay, here we go.
It says here,
"dear joel and da bots--"
- [bots] Hey, dat’s me!
- Right, button it.
Okay, button it, you gums.
Okay, says here,
I have a couple of questions
about tom servo.
- Eh!
- First,
why can’t we
see through tom’s head
when you guys
ares watchin’ the movie?
Even though his head
is tramsparent?
- Huh.
- Hmm, and second?
How can tom
even watch the movie
when he doesn’t have
any peepers?
Well, don’t that
beat the dutch.
Yeah, yeah,
I think old laughin’ boy
is pulling a fast one on us
is what I think.
Hey, what gives,
I ain’t no bad pill!
Honest, fellas,
you’ve been done up brown!
Ah, cut with the baby act.
Come on, clod.
So, dis mug was gonna
give us the boost, huh?
Gonna cut up with diddy-o’s
with his old pallies.
- No, no!
- Why, I oughta--
hey, crow, routine 27.
[All shout]
We’re just pullin’ your pants,
gumpy, take it easy.
Yeah, boy oh boy, we really
had you by
the fat end, pally.
D’ah, you saps.
Hey, hey, foot it, boys.
His nibs is callin’
on the other line.
So what’s it to you,
einstein?
Look, you bombastic
biscuit boy,
anymore of this faux
dead end kids patois
and i’ll teach you
the real meaning
of lexiphanicism
- or what--
- hey, boss, this is good grub.
That padre,
he’s not a half-bad egg.
You know, I could really get
into eating grub like this
if I could be
a junior g-man.
Frank, why must you always
go on with your little--
hey, boss,
do your leo gorcey.
- Come on, you do a great
- i’m not going to do my leo--
he does a great leo--
do your leo gorcey, c’mon.
- Come on. Come on.
- No, frank, frank,
once again, i’m going
to have to kill you.
You wanna run that by me
one more time?
Run that by you
Yeah, you know, kill!
Boost, ice, wack, scrag,
douse, stifle, 86.
Uh, slip the roscoe, chill.
Dust, yank,
toss a little kickshaw.
Roger.
♪♪ [Theme]
Time for go to bed.